(Respect copyright)
♪Memories hold you back
from fulfilling your dreams♪
♪Only by moving forward
can you find reunion♪
♪Endings only mark new routes♪
♪It's all part of the scenery♪
♪To the horizon's call♪
♪Your journey hasn't started♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Let time embrace you
and wash away the past♪
♪Put every twist behind you♪
♪Drift leisurely through time♪
♪Make headway against the wind♪
♪Let mountains bow to your pace♪
♪Rush towards a life without regret♪
♪Let your nature burst free♪
=The First Jasmine=
=Episode 7=
What's the matter?
Ding told me you've accepted the role
as Prefect of Jingzhao Prefecture.
In a few days, you'll take up
your post at Jingzhao Prefecture.
Indeed.
Why?
You've been idle for years,
and you've got the leg problem.
Why are you being assigned now?
Didn't you tell me
not to get trapped
and become a show in others' eyes?
Now I'm pulling myself together,
accepting His Majesty's assignment.
What? Aren't you pleased?
Of course I'm pleased.
Wuyou.
What are you doing?
Just stay silent.
That was Sister-in-law leaving just now?
You go back first.
She's been going out a lot lately.
Who's she meeting?
Wuyou, I have told you
that we are all your family.
If you have any problem
you can't solve, just tell us.
Here.
This is good wine.
(Mo Xiuwen)
So this is that master's residence?
Yes.
What is your mom doing?
These years, after Father's death,
(Sacred Tablet of Late Husband, Mo Xiuwen)
Mom became superstitious,
always praying to deities.
She desperately wanted
to see Father again.
At first, she just spent money,
nothing serious.
But recently, Ms. Zhou
introduced her Immortal Master Wang.
He claims he has powers
to commune with the dead
and can help people see the dead.
He had Mother drink water
from wells at Zi hour every day.
He asked her to eat
raw and uncooked food.
He also asked her to bathe
in black dog's blood,
and made her copy scriptures
with her own blood.
I hate copying scriptures.
Why these frauds
all use the same tricks?
That fraud promised
if she perseveres for forty-nine days,
she will finally see ghosts.
With this mortal form,
I seek to commune with the dead.
Across the three realms,
life and death are separated.
I implore divine power
to light the way to enlightenment!
Drink it.
B-But how could I possibly
swallow the fire?
Open your eyes.
Xiuwen.
Do you see him?
Mom says Immortal Master Wang
truly has great powers.
But anyone starving for over a month
and inhaling that smoke
could see things.
That Immortal Master Wang
is obviously a fraud.
Have you told your uncle any of this
or tried reasoning with your mom?
Ever since Father's death,
Mom was utterly heartbroken.
She even wanted to go after
Father into the netherworld.
She attempted suicide several times,
but was stopped each time.
It terrified everyone in our mansion.
We feared she'd do it again.
She had attempted suicide before?
But after turning to these dark rituals,
she stopped attempting suicide.
I knew this is all illusory.
But it's a good thing
if it calms Mom and gives her hope.
But I never expected that fraud
to exploit her so vilely,
torturing her with such absurd tricks!
Go report this.
Report? Are you...
But what about Mom?
Grave illnesses need potent cures.
Your mom has had this dream
for eight years.
Now it's destroying her.
It's time for her to wake up.
(Qiongying Residence)
Zhao Desheng?
Yes.
Zhao Desheng,
born in Hongzhou City, Jiangnan region.
He was a hooligan.
Relying on government contacts
left by his father,
he became a hired thug
of Constable Li Zhongliang,
exploiting a fortune
under pretense of authority.
When floods struck outside Hongzhou,
he deliberately delayed rescue
to extort victims,
causing the death
of Provincial Governor's son.
After the incident,
he changed his name and hid all the way,
posing as an immortal master,
swindling for profit.
But he only knew my birth chart,
and then could tell
my husband had passed.
Ms. Zhou told him everything.
Ms. Zhou?
Zhao Desheng bribed Ms. Zhou heavily.
Ms. Zhou sold him all your details.
And then she introduced you to him.
Impossible!
Do you think Ms. Zhou would never
leak your information for money,
or Ms. Zhou would never harm you?
Do you know how famous you are
among those charlatans and scoundrels?
Many of them know you spend lavishly,
and are easily deceived.
They all fight
to buy information from Ms. Zhou.
Fifty guan, a hundred guan.
Some are even willing
to pay two hundred guan.
Zhao Desheng wasn't the highest bidder,
but he is the one willing
to offer the most commissions.
After the fraud,
he took a forty percent cut
from the money you donated,
and Ms. Zhou took sixty.
Now Zhao Desheng awaits trial
in Jingzhao Prefecture.
He probably won't be
released in his life.
But...
Ms. Zhou has been staying in our family
and watching me grow up.
Twenty guan for introducing someone.
Fifty guan for a single talisman.
Two hundred guan
for a single offering ceremony.
Such huge profits!
Money,
power,
and time
could change someone the most.
It could turn someone you once knew well
into the one completely unfamiliar.
I intercepted Ms. Zhou when she
tried to flee to escape justice.
She's locked up
in the woodshed right now.
After all, she's your maid.
I should let you decide
what to do about her.
But I...
But I did dream of Xiuwen.
I did dream of him.
I often dream
of my mother.
I really want to see him one more time.
Even in dreams.
(Jingzhao Prefecture)
You stop!
Prince Ding is here to take up his post.
Show me the letter and token.
How dare you!
I'm only following procedures.
Your Highness,
please don't make this difficult.
Show him.
Prince Ding has received
an imperial decree to assume the post
of Prefect of Jingzhao Prefecture.
Want to see it?
I wouldn't dare.
Prince Ding, please.
You, carry me.
I have other duties.
From now on, carrying me
to duty daily is your duty.
Yes.
(Hall of Impartial Justice)
- Greetings, Prefect.
(Deputy Prefect of Jingzhao Prefecture)
I'm Deputy Prefect of Jingzhao Prefecture,
(Zheng Zuoshi)
Zheng Zuoshi.
Greetings, Prefect.
Both of you have been out
for duty since Mou hour,
and only just returned now.
Any findings?
Prefect,
I accompanied Deputy Prefect Zheng
to inspect the East Market.
The merchants are deeply dissatisfied
with the temporary levies.
(Revenue Clerk of Jingzhao Prefecture)
Some even threatened
(Li Yufeng)
to jointly close shops in protest.
How unruly!
I only took on post today.
When did I order any levies?
You're new here, so you don't know.
Did you order the levies?
The remaining funds in the accounts
of Jingzhao Prefecture have run out.
I asked if you ordered the levies.
Exactly.
Then, Deputy Prefect,
please go appease these merchants.
If they close shops in protest,
don't blame me for charging you
with dereliction of duty.
Understood.
Anything else to report?
If not...
(Military Secretary
of Jingzhao Prefecture, Wang Suwu)
You are Prince Ding?
Only official rank matters here.
You should address me as Prefect.
I am Military Secretary Wang Suwu.
Greetings, Prefect.
The murdered soldiers and civilians
of Xiaoshui County at Suixue Pass
and 27 wronged souls of my Wang family,
send you their regards.
How dare you!
I am the Military Secretary,
appointed by the Ministry of Personnel,
ranked Grade Seven, lower class.
May I ask what position do you hold?
Of what rank?
What authority do you have
to reprimand me here?
You!
The regards from murdered soldiers
and civilians of Xiaoshui County
and 27 wronged souls
of your Wang family,
I have
received them.
(Prince Ding's Mansion)
Your Highness.
Ms. Wen is waiting for you
in the main hall.
If not for Li this time,
I'd still be kept in the dark,
and nearly made a terrible mistake.
Ever since your elder brother
passed away,
I've been drowning in grief
and couldn't pull myself out,
so I neglected those around me
and showed no concern for Wuyou.
I-I deserve death!
Please don't say that.
You should blame me.
With elder brother gone, I should
have taken better care of you and Wuyou.
It was my oversight
that put you in danger
and allowed Wuyou to be bullied.
How could I blame you?
You haven't had it easy all these years.
I'm glad to see you
pull yourself together.
Xiuyao.
You must pull yourself together.
No matter what,
we should all stick together
and stay safe, which matters the most.
Now that we have Li,
our life will surely get better.
Please thank Li for me.
I shall take my leave.
Where is the Princess Consort?
Her...
Where is Her Highness?
Hurry!
Hurry! Stand still!
Apologize now!
- We have behaved improperly.
- We have behaved improperly
- We bullied our classmate.
- We beg you for forgiveness, Young Lord.
(Qinglu Academy)
What's wrong?
I'm telling you,
I saw it clearly just now.
The parents of those kids
were gritting their teeth in fury.
They're bound to get a beating.
They weren't sincere in their apology.
They apologized
only because they had to.
I was injured
and of higher status than them.
They apologized to me
only because they were scared.
So what?
Who cares if they are sincere?
Today, you need to show them
that even if they are reluctant,
you still can make them apologize.
If they really regret it,
you accept their apology.
If they don't, you can make them fear.
I see.
Besides, today was just
a minor punishment and a stern warning.
If they dare try again,
I will have plenty of ways
to deal with them.
Like what?
Many ways! We have your uncle.
He is now the Prefect
of Jingzhao Prefecture.
Many spoiled brats have been locked up
in Jingzhao Prefecture prison.
Wouldn't that make us bullies
who abuse our power?
Of course not.
If someone commits a crime,
like assault,
shouldn't the Jingzhao Prefecture
protect its citizens?
We are citizens as well.
Moreover,
even if he weren't the Prefect,
he is still your uncle,
and I am his Princess Consort.
He ought to stand up for us
whenever we face trouble.
Uncle.
Where have you been?
Collecting debts.
Aunt took me to the academy
and made those classmates
who bullied me apologize to me.
If the academy is stifling,
you can go to the Chongwen Institute.
I have arranged it.
You can start next month.
I won't leave. I'm not afraid of them.
Right, don't be afraid.
Then I'll let two guards accompany you.
No, thanks, Uncle.
Aunt said she'd have Ding accompany me.
What about a page boy
skilled in martial arts?
For a bunch of kids brawling,
no need for martial arts masters.
Ding alone is enough.
Let's eat.
What's the matter?
Did you burn yourself?
It's okay.
Y-Your Highness,
he has been very busy lately,
with internal heat rising
and causing mouth sores.
During my time on the mountain,
in winter, we couldn't get fresh greens,
and often got mouth sores.
So, I always carry medicine.
Let me apply this for you.
No need, you two eat first.
Open your mouth.
Here?
Found it.
This medicine is made by me,
so it's not bitter at all.
Your Highness, you've been
shutting yourself in your room all day,
even avoiding the sun.
And you don't like eating.
You're practically inviting these sores.
Done.
Apply it once more tonight.
I'll do it myself.
Okay.
Earlier in the mansion,
I ran into Sister-in-law.
She asked me to thank you for her.
What about you?
You thanked me for Sister-in-law.
Don't you want to thank me yourself?
Thank...
Forget it. We are a couple.
Your sister-in-law is mine.
Your nephew is also mine.
So, no need to thank me.
Have this.
It's to relieve internal heat.
You have some too.
Mo Xiuyao,
let me heal your legs.
Master Helai on Lishan Mountain
is a renowned master physician.
He once wrote the Treatise
on Injuries and Diseases. Heard of it?
I learned how to treat
bone injury from him.
And I treated similar cases
up in the mountains.
Jin has been supporting you
to stand and sit every day.
Your legs can bear some weight,
and aren't completely numb.
Let me try.
There might still be a chance.
Uncle, Aunt, I'm full.
You two enjoy your meal.
I'll go buy some desserts.
Your Highness, Wuyou isn't safe alone.
I'll go protect him. Come on.
- Your Highness.
- Go ahead.
Then I...
Why do you leave?
His Highness is about to get angry.
It's to relieve internal heat.
You know Wei Zhuang,
the steward at my shop, right?
He was my senior at Lishan Academy.
His leg was injured before,
and he has limped for many years.
I'm currently treating him.
He says my treatment works
better than that of the physicians.
And the pain has lessened significantly.
I remember your legs hurt
on cloudy days too, don't they?
Let's eat first.
We'll talk about that later.
Alright.
(Tuisi Pavilion)
My Lady, don't rush.
I don't.
This jade piece is perfect
for the Master's birthday.
Madam will be pleased.
Is this price acceptable?
This item is truly excellent.
Both of you have good taste.
This is quite beautiful.
You two, what else
would you like to see?
The brushwork is elegant,
and the vibe is ethereal.
Truly a fine piece.
Last year in Suzhou, I heard
genuine pieces are hard to find.
Its glaze resembles blood.
Look at this iron sword. The characters
incised at the scabbard throat.
Come on, take a look.
The signature seal stamp is still
clearly identifiable after a century.
This painting was sought out
for me by my friends
in the Grain Tribute Gang
from an old estate in Jiangnan.
If you hang it in your hall,
it will enhance elegance,
and you will also earn a fortune
by reselling it.
Zhou, put the treasure away for now.
Okay.
Don't! I'll take it.
Thank you, dear guests!
This way, please.
Your Highness,
we made a huge profit again.
Back in his days at Lishan Academy,
Senior Wei Zhuang
was already renowned
for his great memory,
and mastery of arithmetic and commerce.
If he had served as an official,
it'd be easy for him to rise and soar.
Running a few shops
is mere child's play for him.
Master Wei is truly formidable.
Murder!
Uncle Wenshen?
Pretend you don't see me.
Ye Wenshen, you villain!
Ye Wenshen, come out now!
Where are you hiding? Come out!
Have you seen him?
No.
If I find you, I'll flay you alive!
Ye Wenshen!
Come out now!
I saw someone heading that way.
Which way?
That way.
Thanks.
(Shende Shop)
What happened exactly?
It's just a misunderstanding.
Mrs. Wang,
the wife of that big and dumb guy,
she often comes to my shop...
She burns incense
and prays for blessings there.
She is devout and generous with money.
You know me.
I interact with everyone
with nothing but gratitude.
So I show her a little extra warmth.
Then rumors started spreading,
saying there's an affair
between her and me.
And that fool believed it
and demanded an explanation.
I thought it's fine.
But before I could utter a word,
he drew a knife and swung it at me.
Thankfully, I was quite agile.
Otherwise, my head
wouldn't be on my shoulders.
I would be chopped to pieces in public!
So is it true?
What?
No way.
Mrs. Wang looks... Let me tell you.
You haven't seen her. She looks...
Even if she's willing, I wouldn't!
I can't go back to Longevity Shop.
My place is also being watched.
Li, let me take shelter at your mansion,
just for a few days.
Why take shelter at my mansion?
Your mansion is safe.
It's Prince Ding's Mansion.
Your husband is Prince Ding,
also the Prefect of Jingzhao Prefecture.
That fool wouldn't dare
cause trouble there!
You've decided. How could I refuse?
Well, Li, you care the most about me.
Your Highness,
I'll get the carriage first.
Li, on second thought,
I need to go back
to Longevity Shop to get some stuff.
I have to stay at your mansion
for a few days.
You go back first.
You aren't afraid
to run into that man again?
I'll go back in via the back door.
Alright, I'll have
a room prepared first.
Good girl.
Your Highness.
Ye Li.
This must be your husband.
Truly, royalty adorned in purple,
and jade belt fitting for a celestial.
This is my uncle, Ye Wenshen,
Master of Longevity Shop.
Niece-in-law.
I might be staying
at your mansion for a while.
I was in a rush today
and forgot to bring a proper gift.
I have high-grade Mengding Shihua tea.
Wait for me. I'll bring some.
The back door is this way?
Wait for me.
He said to stay at our mansion?
Yes.
He got into some trouble.
Someone is demanding his life
outside Longevity Shop.
He's too scared to return,
and he wants to take shelter
at our mansion.
Why doesn't he go back to Ye Mansion?
The most influential
in Ye Mansion is my eldest uncle.
But compared to you,
Prefect of Jingzhao Prefecture,
he's just insignificant.
Uncle Wenshen is clever, seeking refuge
with someone the most powerful.
Are you fine with it?
He is your uncle.
Since you've invited him,
I can only be fine with it.
Have you done all your work today?
Come on. Get in. Let's return together.
- Good!
Thank you!
The monkey got loose!
What happened?
Li!
Ye Li! Are you alright?
What happened?
I'm terribly sorry to startle you.
What's wrong with you?
Control your monkey.
It's fine.
Jin, go back now.
(Prince Ding's Mansion)
Qingshuang, what's wrong?
My Lady, a monkey!
A monkey? Impossible.
That monkey has been caught
by the monkey trainer.
But I saw it, truly!
It was in the courtyard, right there.
It even bit me.
Don't be afraid. I'm here.
Monkey!
I don't see it.
Qingshuang.
Qingshuang?
Where are you, Qingshuang?
Qingshuang.
Who's there?
Your Highness,
what are you doing here alone?
Monkey.
Where did the monkey go?
What happened?
Monkeys!
So many monkeys!
Found none.
Your Highness.
Are you hurt anywhere?
Sister-in-law, I'm fine. Don't worry.
Xiuyao said you saw monkeys
in the mansion?
You must have been seeing things.
The capital is heavily guarded,
and the mansion has high walls.
Monkeys wouldn't run rampant here.
Jackdaws often perch on the rockery
in the west corner of the backyard.
Not jackdaws. Monkeys!
I did not see wrong.
There really are monkeys!
I know you don't believe me.
But I...
Never mind.
Forget it.
Pass down the order. Stay high alert.
Take men and thoroughly search
the perimeter of the mansion again.
Yes!
Then Wuyou and I will
return to our room first.
Rest well.
Aunt, I take my leave.
Your Highness, are you alright?
Should I call a physician
to examine you?
Let her rest first.
Yes.
I remember you once said
there were monkeys on Lishan Mountain.
Would they sneak into the academy?
Yes.
They always came in to steal things.
Not only did they
steal the meals I made,
but also stole my books.
There were so many people
in Lishan Academy.
Weren't monkeys afraid of people?
They even stole things?
Those monkeys were very bold.
I got bitten by them.
See?
It's fine.
I already had Jin patrol the backyard.
Get some rest now.
I promise you won't be scared
by any more monkeys.
I can't sleep.
I'll stay with you.
I won't leave before you fall asleep.
Your Highness, the mansion has been
searched. No monkeys were seen.
Perhaps the Princess Consort
was mistaken?
Send more men
to patrol throughout the night.
Yes.
(Tuisi Pavilion)
An invitation from Prince Li's Mansion?
Is it from Princess Li?
She's inviting you to go on
a painted boat cruise on Chengxin Lake?
I won't go.
(Invitation from Dong Mu of Prince Li's Mansion)
Have you been troubled by the nightmare?
I said it wasn't a nightmare!
I saw many monkeys in the mansion.
Alright. Regardless of
whether it's real or fake,
His Highness believes it.
Why do you say that?
I heard it from Jin.
Today, as soon as His Highness
arrived at the Prefecture, he ordered
that no more monkey shows in the city.
He's doing it because he fears
you might get scared by monkeys again.
Order?
Does Jingzhao Prefecture
have the authority to do so?
He asked the monkey trainers to leave?
It said to be an order, but His Highness
compensated them out of his own pocket.
The men from Jingzhao Prefecture
sent the compensation one by one.
Those monkey trainers were happy
to leave with compensation.
(Preview)
Do you think it doesn't look good?
No. Do you feel coolness?
This must be Prince Ding's
newly-wed princess consort.
Headmaster Xu has authored
countless books.
Why are his words not matched by deeds?
As long as I'm with you,
anywhere is good.
Don't you find yourself ridiculous
when you say these things?
(Memorial tablet of Xu Wanzhou)
♪Memories hold you back
from fulfilling your dreams♪
♪Only by moving forward
can you find reunion♪
♪Endings only mark new routes♪
♪It's all part of the scenery♪
♪To the horizon's call♪
♪Your journey hasn't started♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Both joy and grief
make the trip worthwhile♪
♪Trying to catch up
to your own lost shadow♪
♪Within the wilds, echoes thrive♪
♪Clear mind leads to a clear path♪
♪Be grateful to your losses♪
♪Make your steps weightless♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Let time embrace you
and wash away the past♪
♪Put every twist behind you,
drift leisurely through time♪
♪Make headway against the wind,
let mountains bow to your pace♪
♪Rush towards a life without regret♪
♪Let your nature burst free♪
♪Unbound by form♪